<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Prologue on</title><link>/background/prologue/</link><description>Recent content in Prologue on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/background/prologue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>/background/prologue/introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>/background/prologue/introduction/</guid><description>Although the audience is involved, there often is a separation between the audience and the artists on stage.
In this work, we are exploring means to strengthen the connection between the audience and artists. We present a stage production aiming to integrate the audience into the process of aesthetic creation via physiological sensing. We call this approach &amp;ldquo;Boiling Mind&amp;rdquo;.
To realize &amp;ldquo;Boiling Mind&amp;rdquo;, we expressed physiological signals from the audience during the performance via changes in common staging elements, such as projections, sound, and light elements.</description></item><item><title>Perfromance Details</title><link>/background/prologue/quick-start/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 13:59:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>/background/prologue/quick-start/</guid><description>Requirements In March 2020 we conducted three performances. The performances were advertised mentioning that we will be using the physiological signals and a brief introduction of what would be expected to happen during the performance. All the audience members were asked to read through the consent form on their seats (See Fig.\ref{fig:wrist} Left). By signing the form, they agreed to participate in this work and to offer their physiological data.</description></item><item><title>Implementation</title><link>/background/prologue/commands/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 15:21:01 +0200</pubDate><guid>/background/prologue/commands/</guid><description>The collected physiological data of the audience is transmitted to the server over WiFi. The server re-streams the processed data to other computers controlling each staging element.
Sensing EDA and Heart Activity For this project we built wrist-worn devices measuring EDA from 2 electrodes on the fingers, and the heart rate using an optical blood volume pulse sensor. EDA signal was sampled at 4.545 Hz and the heart rate sensor at 50Hz.</description></item></channel></rss>